<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circumnavigating Cyprus</title>
    <description>Exactly what the title says.
</description>
    <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 09:02:51 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 09:02:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Food of Cyprus</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;keeping-us-fueled&quot;&gt;Keeping us Fueled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve received a few requests for a food post, so here it is. Afiyet Olsun, Kali Orexi, Bon Appetite, Enjoy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_2016_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2016_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are in North or South Cyprus, the food is good, fresh, and plentiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3521.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3521.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3747.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3747.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3755.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3755.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3430.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3430.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh artichokes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1710_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1710_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And fresh snails!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1723_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1723_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were hoping to circumnavigate Cyprus and drop a few kilos in the process, but that might not go according to plan. Sheftalia, Kebab, Mix Pita, Donnor, Durum, Meze, and the list goes on and on. We have thoroughly
enjoyed hiking, and eating, our way through Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4506_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4506_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4513_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4513_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4980.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4980.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1735_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1735_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you order meze be prepared for a lot of food. Similar to Spanish tapas, you will get a variety of small plates with olives, hummus, beats, salad, tahini, mushrooms, fish roe dip, tzatziki, yogurt, capers, etc. Then the main course arrives….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3571.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1087_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1087_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1090_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1090_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3567.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3567.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1989_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1989_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5285.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5285.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the simple meals are good. Halloumi is sold at most gas stations which goes with everything so far. Our favorite camp meal so far is canned sardines, halloumi cheese, fresh bread and dried fruits &amp;amp; nutts. Lemon, of course, garnish almost everything and luckily there are enough lemon trees on this island to fee the Russian army(Don’t get any ideas Putin). SO you never have to look to far to find a fresh squeeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_0895.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0895.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5159.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5159.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, BBQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easter “Souvla” BBQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_0693_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_0693_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beach BBQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2087.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2087.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2105.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2105.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Boat BBQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5824.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5824.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5825.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5825.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/participant%20photography/2016/06/09/the-food-of-cyprus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/participant%20photography/2016/06/09/the-food-of-cyprus/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>participant photography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Unexpected Kindness</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;traveling-through-the-karpaz-peninsula&quot;&gt;Traveling through the Karpaz/Καρπασία Peninsula&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first began our trek through north Cyprus, Vasili and I were unsure of what to expect. We assumed that, because we do not speak Turkish, we’d have a difficult time meeting people, navigating, and finding accommodations.  We quickly realized this would not be the case. Instead, the people of the Karpaz/Καρπασία Peninsula met us with open arms, afternoon coffees, and countless unasked-for rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our journey from St. Barnabas monastery, just north of Famagusta. We expected to have a long 8-mile day of hiking up the coast, but within 10 minutes of our trek a man in a work truck pulled up alongside us and told us to get in. We did not intend to hitchhike, but the man insisted he take us a few kilometers to the nearest town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4770.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought this unexpected act of kindness was something we’d only experience once on our journey. But shortly after parting ways with our new friend, another kind stranger offered us a ride. And throughout our whole journey we’ve received such kindness, often times despite our limited ability communicate. Although we do not know everyone by name, and cannot thank everyone here, here are a few examples of such kindness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4960.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4960.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4964.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4964.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cafer Özkul, a landscape designer originally from Turkey, offered us a ride, and welcomed us into his home for Turkish coffee and a smoke. His family and neighbor gathered to have coffee with us. After coffee, Cafer insisted he drive us another few kilometers to the next village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5756.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5756.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5757.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5757.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5758.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5758.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of Turkish Cypriot carpenters from Yeni Erenköy/ Γιαλούσα welcomed us into their workshop for an afternoon coffee when they noticed us passing through the village. These men spent nearly 15 years working as carpenters in south Cyprus, and were happy that we could communicate in Greek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5780new.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5780new.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_5770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5770.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murtaza Sari, a petrol driver from originally from Turkey, gave us a ride in his work truck, and treated us to lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words cannot express how grateful we are to these and the countless others who have shown us unyielding generosity during our journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/06/05/an-unexpected-kindness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/06/05/an-unexpected-kindness/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>trekking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Diverse Village</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;dipkarpaz-to-some-rizokarpaso-to-others&quot;&gt;Dipkarpaz to some, Rizokarpaso to others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5034_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5034_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent one night in the village of Dipkarpaz/Rizokarpaso. This is a village in the far north where some Greek Cypriots were allowed to stay after 1974. Our 15 hours in this beautiful village was well spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5060_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5060_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first met Christina, a resident of Rizokarpaso since she was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4999_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4999_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has always lived among Turkish Cypriots and knows there is no problem with the two living in harmony. Since her husband passed away five years ago, the Turkish Cypriot people of the village have been very kind to her and lend a helping hand when she needs it. “Whether you pray to our God or their Allah, it’s the same thing. The same God.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5001_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5001_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was feeling a little scruffy so I got a shave from the Turkish barber. The barbershop was awesome. A boys club in the village where they served coffee and hung out. And although I could not understand the language, banter amongst the boys that seemed friendly continually bounced about the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5130_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5130_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5075_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5075_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5125_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5125_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5068_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5068_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5132_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5132_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also met Tassos, a Greek Cypriot man who was born in Rizokarpaso. He was in Rizokarpaso visiting for the weekend. In July of 1977 at the age of eight, he and he family were forced to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5176_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5176_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Turkish military expelled us from here. From our home. ” Tassos said with a tone that reinforced his frustration for the events that took place; the effects of which he still feels today. “My father had 100 ‘skales’ (1 Skala = 14,400 sq. ft) of farmland. It is gone. I can’t go to my father’s home, the home where I was born. Someone else lives there. It’s not right…My father still lives in the south. He is 73. He won’t come here to visit. He can’t go to his home, he can’t go to his fields. What’s he going to do here? He will just get mad, so he stays in the south.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5168_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5168_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tassos believes that a solution is possible. But he believes that the Turkish government should take back all of the immigrants it sent to Cyprus and give the occupied land back to the rightful owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_5171_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_5171_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked if he was okay with me writing what we had discussed, he replied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Write it. I’m not afraid. I don’t have a problem with it. I am a Greek. A Greek Cypriot.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/06/01/a-diverse-village/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/06/01/a-diverse-village/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;They must trust each other.&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;talking-with-gnay&quot;&gt;Talking with Günay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4813.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4813.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we began our walk from Famagusta up to the Karpaz peninsula we stopped at a local market to purchase water and snacks for the long trek ahead. There we met storeowner Günay Can, a Turkish Cypriot originally from a small village near Laranca. While we only chatted briefly, Günay simply and eloquently explained some of the challenges that must be overcome before unification can be reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They must trust each other.” He said, referring to Greek and Turkish Cypriots. “Otherwise, it’s difficult.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4796.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4796.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Günay often visits his childhood home in south Cyprus, and he has no problem crossing the border. Still, he says some people are scared of reunification, and he thinks more time is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People must feel safe.” He said. “Safety is the most important thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_4818.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4818.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/29/they-must-trust-each-other/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/29/they-must-trust-each-other/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Into the North</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;hanging-out-with-kemal&quot;&gt;Hanging out with Kemal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4518_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4518_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the UN Buffer Zone in Agios Nikolaos and spent two days in Famagusta with our host and devout heavy metal enthusiast, Kemal. We first got together with Kemal for a Meze lunch in the old city of Famagusta that is still lined with Venitian walls and gates. The main gate was designed by Leonardo Da Vinci.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_0827.JPG.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0827.JPG.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’re a Turkish Cypriot?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, but first I consider myself Cypriot.  We Cypriots have many commonalities. Culturally, our foods, our communication, we are both very loud (everyone at the table laughs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…So can the island be unified?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I believe people can live together everywhere. Turkish Cypriots and Greek Cypriots live together in London and Australia, why can’t the live together here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unification process, though, will not be easy. “To pass the referendum is one thing. To implement it is another. And to truly achieve peace is yet another very hard thing to be achieved.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is very hopeful for the unification of north and south Cyprus. Kemal believes it needs to be done in the immediate future. “The Turkish Cypriot identity is in serious danger right now…the problem is that there is a population shift to the island from Turkey, so you see Turkish Cypriots assimilating to Turkish customs and ways, creating on the island a Turkish identity, not a Cypriot identity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our excellent host also took us to the Ancient City of Salamis at dusk. We were the only ones there and it was incredible. It was our very own ancient playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4536_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4536_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_0834.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0834.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4575_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4575_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4559_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4559_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4555_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4555_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4678_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4678_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4583_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4583_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4619_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4619_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_4630_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_4630_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/26/into-the-north/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/26/into-the-north/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deryneia: A village on the border.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-resolution-of-course&quot;&gt;“A resolution, of course.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3038.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3038.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we traveled to Deryneia to meet Marios, a young veterinarian, and his mother, Flora, a schoolteacher. Deryneia is a village on the buffer zone set back from the east coast of Cyprus. Here, more than anywhere else we’ve been so far, we felt a desire for a resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3046.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3046.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first arrived, Marios and Flora took us on a tour of Deryneia. An integral part of this village is the border. After 1974 much of the villages’ agricultural fields and access to the sea was cut off by the established UN buffer zone. From the car, Flora showed us her sister’s house, brand new in 1974, and now inaccessible. Cypriot and Turkish outposts are located on either side of the barbed wire denoting a buffer zone approximately half a mile wide, with United Nations outposts sandwiched in between. In the background lies Varosha, the once-bustling tourism area of Famagusta turned ghost town after 1974.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3062.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3062.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Deryneia the divide is an obvious and ever-present part of life, and people want a resolution. Flora spoke of the 2004 vote, saying that in Deryneia the overwhelming majority voted yes on the referendum. It was those living away from the border that may have benefited from the flood of tourism to the south after the division and therefore do not feel compelled to reunify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3078.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3078.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our tour we stopped at Marios flat, located adjacent to the buffer zone, to view Famagusta from the rooftop. When discussing the future of Cyprus, Marios spoke of the complexity of the situation and stressed that there is no easy solution.  To Marios, it is important to remember that during times of war both parties committed crimes and both parties carry some blame. While Marios wishes for a resolution, he remains realistic in his expectations and is acutely aware that Cyprus cannot be what it was prior to 1974.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3093.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning Marios and his cousin, Petros, took us to visit a church located within the buffer zone. With the approval of the UN guard, we took a ten-minute stroll into this no-mans land to visit Ayias Marinas.  On this walk, we spoke to Petros about what he envisions for the future of Cyprus. When asked what he would like to see for Cyprus he said “a resolution, of course.” Despite voting against the 2004 referendum Petros says he would vote for any future referendum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_3147.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3147.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After 40 years of separation no one trusts each other, so you must work at it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 2004 vote, Petros believes that Cyprus cannot wait for a perfect solution, but must unify first and work towards equality together. Like Marios, Petros knows that Cyprus cannot be what it was in the 1960s. Still he believes that, given the opportunity, young Greek and Turkish Cypriots would try to live together and form a Cypriot community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/21/deryneia-a-village-on-the-border/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/21/deryneia-a-village-on-the-border/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yolda bulunan bir hazine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bugün Zygi’den Matazos’a yürüdük. Zygi ve Matazos, Kıbrıs’ın Larnaca bölgesinde iki küçük balıkçı köyü. Yolculuk sırasında Maroni’de bir arkeolojik bir sit alanını ziyaret ettik, ve alanda antik harabelerden fazlasını bulduk. Gelecek durak, Kiti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2009.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/trekking/2016/05/15/yolda-bulunan-bir-hazine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/trekking/2016/05/15/yolda-bulunan-bir-hazine/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>trekking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Takım Üyeleri Mercek Altında: Vasili</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;vasili-sotiropulosla-tann&quot;&gt;Vasili Sotiropulos’la tanışın&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merhaba! Ben Vasili. Son bir sene içerisinde hayatım epey değişti. Geçen sonbaharda sabah 9 akşam 5’lik işimden bir senelik bir macera için istifa ettim. İşimi bırakıp evimden taşınalı beri de arkama bakmadım. O günden bu yana Meksika’nın Pasifik kıyısında ve Karayiplerde yelken yaptım, Oregon’da karlarda yürüdüm, Long Beach’ten Montana’ya arabayla gittim, Alaska’da buzullara gezindim, ve Güney Kaliforniya kıyısında sörf yaptım.  Fakat en fazla heyecan duyduğum serüven bir sonraki… Kıbrıs’takı seyahatimiz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bu keşif gezisi, bana adanın sosyokültürel manzarasına birinci elden gözlem ile doğa sevgimi kaynaştırma fırsatı sunuyor. En çok bilinmeyenler hakkında heyecanlıyım. Kiminle tanışacağız? Ne öğreneceğiz? Nasıl sorunları çözeceğiz? Ne bulacağız?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oluşturduğumuz olağanüstü ekibimizin tüm üyelerinin kökeni Akdeniz’de. Yolculuğumuzda çok faydalı olacak eklektik bir bilgi ve beceri kümemiz var. Bunun ötesinde bu ekibi ailem olarak görüyorum, ve beraber atacağımız ilk adımı iple çekiyorum.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-fra3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xat1/v/t1.0-0/q84/p206x206/11218455_1695064557381511_397204977700404661_n.jpg?oh=defc8d7b79c8270293624a56bdef123d&amp;amp;oe=57A6FF85&quot; alt=&quot;V yosemite&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-fra3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/t31.0-8/12471872_10153851739748844_7079054740535570838_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vsailing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_1262.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;V alaska&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/tak-m-yeleri-mercek-alt-nda-vasili/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/tak-m-yeleri-mercek-alt-nda-vasili/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nasıl başladı...</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;gezimizin-douu&quot;&gt;Gezimizin Doğuşu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bütün iyi fikirler gibi bu gezi, yakın arkadaşlarla yenen keyifli bir yemek, ve yemek sırasında içilen bol miktarda şarapla ortaya çıktı.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 yazında bunaltıcı sıcaklıkta bir akşamdı. Teyzelerim, amcalarım, kuzenlerim, ve kardeşlerimle beraber Parekklisia, Kıbrıs’ta bir tavernada oturuyorduk. İşte burada ben, ağabeyim, ve kuzenim adayı baştan aşağı yürümeye karar verdik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben ve erkek kardeşim Kaliforniya’da büyüdüğümüzden dolayı bütün eyaleti boydan boya katettiğimiz araba yolculuklarına alışkınız. Bu yüzden Kıbrıs’ı ne zaman ziyaret etsek adanın büyüklüğü bizi şaşırtırdı. 2014 yılındaki bu aile ziyareti sırasındaysa kuzenlerimizin Kuzey Kıbrıs’ın Türk işgaline bakış açısının anne babalarınınkinden çok farklı olduğunu farkettik. Adayı dolaşmanın, ve yol boyunca Kıbrıslılarla konuşmanın, Kıbrıs kimliğinin gerçek anlamını anlamamıza yardımcı olacağına karar verdik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yaklaşık iki sene sonra, National Geographic Genç Kaşifler hibesine başvurup ödülümüzü aldıktan, destekçilerimizin bağışladığı 6000 dolarlık bir meblağı bütçemize kattıktan, ve Vasili’yi ekibimize ekledikten sonra sonunda yürüyüşe başlıyoruz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kıbrıs kimliğinin resimleri, videoları, ve öyküleri için bizi izlemeye devam edin – Yunan, Türk, ve aralarındaki her şey için!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/how it started.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;how it started.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/nas-l-ba-lad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/nas-l-ba-lad/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keşif Hazırlıkları: Gün 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;antoniou-iftlii-ziyareti&quot;&gt;Antoniou Çiftliği Ziyareti&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dün, takım üyemiz Vasili, ve websitesi tasarımcımız Ori, Kıbrıs’a ayak bastı. Onları adaya ısındırmak için, Takis Amca’mın çiftliği Antoniou Çiftliği’ni ziyaret ettik.&lt;a href=&quot;http://antoniouplantations.com/&quot;&gt;The Antoniou Plantation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amcam bize çiftliğini gezdirdikten sonra, bize çevredeki ziraii işlerden bahsetti. Bize ağaçtan &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceratonia_siliqua&quot;&gt;keçiboynuzu&lt;/a&gt; yemeyi öğretti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tzhmhwbybko32aa/IMG_1448.jpg?dl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Uncle Takis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keçiboynuzu Doğu Akdeniz’de sıkça bulunan bir ağaç; meyvesi öğütülerek toz haline getirilebilir, ince ince dilimlenebilir, ya da çikolata niyetine kullanılabilecek şurubu yapılabilir. Kıbrıs’ta, keçiboynuzu şurubu, “Kıbrıs’ın kara altını” olarak bilinir, ve Kıbrıs’ın ithal ettiği ürünlerin başında gelir. Ama biz ağaçtan yemeyi tercih ediyoruz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ljonx20hxi9nf7a/Ori.jpg?dl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Ori eats a carob pod&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Önümüzdeki bir iki gün boyunca, yürüyüş için hazırlık yapıyor ve Parekklisia’daki Paskalya (Πάσχα) şenliklerini keşfediyor olacağız. Sizlere ailemizin köyünü ve daha fazlasını göstermeyi sabırsızlıkla bekliyoruz!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/ke-if-haz-rl-klar-g-n-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/ke-if-haz-rl-klar-g-n-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
