<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circumnavigating Cyprus</title>
    <description>Exactly what the title says.
</description>
    <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 11:58:17 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 11:58:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yolda bulunan bir hazine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bugün Zygi’den Matazos’a yürüdük. Zygi ve Matazos, Kıbrıs’ın Larnaca bölgesinde iki küçük balıkçı köyü. Yolculuk sırasında Maroni’de bir arkeolojik bir sit alanını ziyaret ettik, ve alanda antik harabelerden fazlasını bulduk. Gelecek durak, Kiti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2009.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/05/15/yolda-bulunan-bir-hazine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/05/15/yolda-bulunan-bir-hazine/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>trekking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Takım Üyeleri Mercek Altında: Vasili</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;vasili-sotiropulosla-tann&quot;&gt;Vasili Sotiropulos’la tanışın&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merhaba! Ben Vasili. Son bir sene içerisinde hayatım epey değişti. Geçen sonbaharda sabah 9 akşam 5’lik işimden bir senelik bir macera için istifa ettim. İşimi bırakıp evimden taşınalı beri de arkama bakmadım. O günden bu yana Meksika’nın Pasifik kıyısında ve Karayiplerde yelken yaptım, Oregon’da karlarda yürüdüm, Long Beach’ten Montana’ya arabayla gittim, Alaska’da buzullara gezindim, ve Güney Kaliforniya kıyısında sörf yaptım.  Fakat en fazla heyecan duyduğum serüven bir sonraki… Kıbrıs’takı seyahatimiz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bu keşif gezisi, bana adanın sosyokültürel manzarasına birinci elden gözlem ile doğa sevgimi kaynaştırma fırsatı sunuyor. En çok bilinmeyenler hakkında heyecanlıyım. Kiminle tanışacağız? Ne öğreneceğiz? Nasıl sorunları çözeceğiz? Ne bulacağız?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oluşturduğumuz olağanüstü ekibimizin tüm üyelerinin kökeni Akdeniz’de. Yolculuğumuzda çok faydalı olacak eklektik bir bilgi ve beceri kümemiz var. Bunun ötesinde bu ekibi ailem olarak görüyorum, ve beraber atacağımız ilk adımı iple çekiyorum.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-fra3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xat1/v/t1.0-0/q84/p206x206/11218455_1695064557381511_397204977700404661_n.jpg?oh=defc8d7b79c8270293624a56bdef123d&amp;amp;oe=57A6FF85&quot; alt=&quot;V yosemite&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-fra3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/t31.0-8/12471872_10153851739748844_7079054740535570838_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vsailing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_1262.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;V alaska&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/tak-m-yeleri-mercek-alt-nda-vasili/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/tak-m-yeleri-mercek-alt-nda-vasili/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nasıl başladı...</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;gezimizin-douu&quot;&gt;Gezimizin Doğuşu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bütün iyi fikirler gibi bu gezi, yakın arkadaşlarla yenen keyifli bir yemek, ve yemek sırasında içilen bol miktarda şarapla ortaya çıktı.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 yazında bunaltıcı sıcaklıkta bir akşamdı. Teyzelerim, amcalarım, kuzenlerim, ve kardeşlerimle beraber Parekklisia, Kıbrıs’ta bir tavernada oturuyorduk. İşte burada ben, ağabeyim, ve kuzenim adayı baştan aşağı yürümeye karar verdik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben ve erkek kardeşim Kaliforniya’da büyüdüğümüzden dolayı bütün eyaleti boydan boya katettiğimiz araba yolculuklarına alışkınız. Bu yüzden Kıbrıs’ı ne zaman ziyaret etsek adanın büyüklüğü bizi şaşırtırdı. 2014 yılındaki bu aile ziyareti sırasındaysa kuzenlerimizin Kuzey Kıbrıs’ın Türk işgaline bakış açısının anne babalarınınkinden çok farklı olduğunu farkettik. Adayı dolaşmanın, ve yol boyunca Kıbrıslılarla konuşmanın, Kıbrıs kimliğinin gerçek anlamını anlamamıza yardımcı olacağına karar verdik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yaklaşık iki sene sonra, National Geographic Genç Kaşifler hibesine başvurup ödülümüzü aldıktan, destekçilerimizin bağışladığı 6000 dolarlık bir meblağı bütçemize kattıktan, ve Vasili’yi ekibimize ekledikten sonra sonunda yürüyüşe başlıyoruz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kıbrıs kimliğinin resimleri, videoları, ve öyküleri için bizi izlemeye devam edin – Yunan, Türk, ve aralarındaki her şey için!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/how it started.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;how it started.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/nas-l-ba-lad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/nas-l-ba-lad/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keşif Hazırlıkları: Gün 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;antoniou-iftlii-ziyareti&quot;&gt;Antoniou Çiftliği Ziyareti&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dün, takım üyemiz Vasili, ve websitesi tasarımcımız Ori, Kıbrıs’a ayak bastı. Onları adaya ısındırmak için, Takis Amca’mın çiftliği Antoniou Çiftliği’ni ziyaret ettik.&lt;a href=&quot;http://antoniouplantations.com/&quot;&gt;The Antoniou Plantation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amcam bize çiftliğini gezdirdikten sonra, bize çevredeki ziraii işlerden bahsetti. Bize ağaçtan &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceratonia_siliqua&quot;&gt;keçiboynuzu&lt;/a&gt; yemeyi öğretti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tzhmhwbybko32aa/IMG_1448.jpg?dl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Uncle Takis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keçiboynuzu Doğu Akdeniz’de sıkça bulunan bir ağaç; meyvesi öğütülerek toz haline getirilebilir, ince ince dilimlenebilir, ya da çikolata niyetine kullanılabilecek şurubu yapılabilir. Kıbrıs’ta, keçiboynuzu şurubu, “Kıbrıs’ın kara altını” olarak bilinir, ve Kıbrıs’ın ithal ettiği ürünlerin başında gelir. Ama biz ağaçtan yemeyi tercih ediyoruz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ljonx20hxi9nf7a/Ori.jpg?dl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Ori eats a carob pod&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Önümüzdeki bir iki gün boyunca, yürüyüş için hazırlık yapıyor ve Parekklisia’daki Paskalya (Πάσχα) şenliklerini keşfediyor olacağız. Sizlere ailemizin köyünü ve daha fazlasını göstermeyi sabırsızlıkla bekliyoruz!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/ke-if-haz-rl-klar-g-n-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/ke-if-haz-rl-klar-g-n-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kıbrıs Hakkında Ufak bir Yazı</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;kbrs-meselesinin-ksa-ve-fazla-basitletirilmi-bir-tarihi&quot;&gt;Kıbrıs Meselesi’nin Kısa ve Fazla Basitleştirilmiş bir Tarihi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kıbrıs, Akdeniz’deki merkezi konumu, AB üyeliği, ve muazzam güzelliğine rağmen, Avrupa dışında fazla bilinmeyen bir ada. Çoğu zaman mevzu bahis Kıbrıs olunca varsayılan konuşmanın a) bir ağaç, b) ismini bir ağaçtan almış bir Güney Kaliforniya şehri, c) kara para aklama, veya d) eski bir yasal doktrin hakkında olduğu varsayılır. Esasında Kıbrıs, size Cat Stevens (Yusuf İslam), George Michael, ve hellimi vermiş olan Doğu Akdeniz’in kalbinde bölünmüş bir adadır.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kıbrıs, 70 seneden uzun sürmüş olan İngiliz egemenliğinden sonra, 1960 yılından 1974’e kadar kısa süreliğine bağımsız bir ülkeydi. Etnik Türk-Rum ilişkileri açısından sıkıntılı geçen bu 14 senenin sonunda Yunanistan’daki askeri diktatörlüğün adayı ele geçirmek için düzenlediği darbeyle ada ikiye bölündü. Etnik Türklerin adına duruma müdahele eden Türkiye, adanın yaklaşık yüzde 37’sini işgal etti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_ori.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_ori.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Günümüzde mesele hala çıkmazda, ada güneyde Rumlar ve kuzeyde Türkler olmak üzere bölünmüş durumda. 1974 yılından önce Rum ve Türk kökenli Kıbrıslılar ada boyunca eşit bir şekilde dağılmıştı. Bugün, adanın kuzeyinde çok az sayıda Rum, güneyindeyse çok az sayıda Türk bulunmaktadır. Adayı bütünleştirmek adına bazısı umut veren bir sürü teşebbüs oldu, fakat sonuçta adayı ikiye bölen tel örgüler hala yerinde durmakta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent.fath3-2.fna.fbcdn.net/t31.0-8/13116047_1157624697602684_6687651883232887284_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yaklaşık 10 seneden beri Kuzey’i Güney’den ayıran sınırı geçmek mümkün. Bu gezi boyunca sınırın iki yanındaki toplululukların konuya bakışlarını inceleyeceğiz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/k-br-s-hakk-nda-ufak-bir-yaz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/tr/team%20member%20updates/2016/05/15/k-br-s-hakk-nda-ufak-bir-yaz/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tr</category>
        
        <category>team member updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stella’s Story</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-first-hand-account&quot;&gt;A First-Hand Account&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_2001_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2001_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in Larnaca we stayed one night with Nicolas and his mother Stella. Before the Turkish occupation of northern Cyprus, Stella and her family had moved to the U.K. because her husband had found work there. But in 1974 Stella had returned to her village of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Dipkarpaz+936140/@35.6081466,34.3069812,11z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x14df676bb777dc15:0x2838425b34dd7122!8m2!3d35.6176824!4d34.4087307&quot;&gt;Rizokarpaso&lt;/a&gt;(in the north) with her four children because her mother had passed away; her husband had stayed behind to work in England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Greek Cypriots of Rizocarpaso had learned that Turkish troops had entered the island and cut off the north from the south, they knew they could not escape to the south so they hid in the forest. Stella described the night as:
“Terrifying…It was the most fearful night of my life. We did not sleep that night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_2028_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2028_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neighboring village of Galinoporni, populated by Turkish Cypriots were good friends of the Rizokarpaso residents. Stella said they were extremely close, like “brothers and sisters”. Her friends in Galinoporni spoke to the Turkish troops explained their relationship, asking the troops to leave the village alone. Stella credits her friend’s actions for their safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, She would like to see Cyprus unified and she believes the Turkish Cypriot friends she remembers would want the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We all want Cyprus to be unified so we can all go back to our homes and our land. Our families were farmers. We lived off this land and we want to go back to it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/your-filename/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/your-filename/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Egyptian Shepherd</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cypriot-identity-without-cypriot-blood&quot;&gt;Cypriot identity without Cypriot blood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_1341.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1341.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Najib, a shepherd from Egypt. We met Najib while passing through the village of Agios Theodoros on May 5th.  Najib came to Cyprus on a work visa four months ago to escape the political unrest occurring in Egypt. As an Egyptian, Najib can only hold a work visa in Cyprus for six months.  Although he is not from Cyprus and will soon have to leave, Najib spoke very highly of Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_1463.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1463.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we travel, we are beginning to realize that this island is inhabited and loved by more than just Greek and Turkish Cypriots and the Cypriot identity is embodied by people of many different ethnicities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/the-egyptian-shepard/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/the-egyptian-shepard/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;We are the same people.&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-parea-at-mikri-landa-beach&quot;&gt;New parea at Mikri Landa Beach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2246.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2246.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday Panikos Loizou welcomed us into his family.  We met Panikos, his family, and his friends, while we were walking along the coast near Ayia Napa.  We were looking for a shady place to rest, when a large group having a barbeque greeted us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello! Welcome! Come eat!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slowed our pace, puzzled by such a warm welcome thrust upon strangers. But their invitations kept coming and it didn’t take much to convince us that their freshly caught fish was more appetizing than our anticipated lunch of granola bars and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_2087.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2087.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/82D8RnL5ORk3ZWww5gy9XTCJtCXPFJOUriYNO_ivNKWd13pxOEVBeiAu4IYqSldG1F4z83wMestu1EAXg0XTBB1mstQNwxC7YnJRZK4LsVFmRB17xXxWVNxdkEhOo4vNJmIvnFe6tNEzJ-M7j9Dh0Bt3qlr7RHOR3AR-HLK580BRE0VXiBogcB8NtNwGG35Rt-F1tJGQ1b8Q8eCvP-2GDG-byQ-2WJJfq6uDM3dl2gGeMlVzO3xvSJSeuU0GYIYeOV6Kt_B12h9UQZvieT_C3jgk-1Foa0V1Q1eCq-Jkuj_08FXT8nONKELlTFjrxAVVmyoOfSTJLBYasjkYaWf4AVMoa102reM3LRR7xm6KSPuH4iUyyW479WnOUGCP01lFaudaMsBve-RUwUm-IR286-SdIau4A_cV8vX8jX4kzKB685K_4oCHq0m6Qv7YgU89FbORBYnCHQNjg_m3Wag14mGSqB_zf1riPGZQxzt_su24he8udlqWatRyIfQqiEk3okQObpJJb90MLm53XuL0rnI2Hu-DSNBhHlZlBCEJMe37F73OlDdPDmp-oXqaSoVYCMX3ce9fEUa8edS2R4TZxhdxjpr6Ptg=w1916-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;everyone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the table was a hodgepodge of Cypriots. Costa, Panikos, Kakia, and Christakis are Greek Cypriots from various cities around Cyprus. But there was also Krisztina from Romania, Marie Ann, Glenn, and Adam from England, and a woman from Philippines—all of whom have immigrated to Cyprus and live here permanently. Every Sunday, this group of friends gather on the same beach for a barbeque, each bringing food or drink to share with the party. Here they are all Cypriot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/DGeI9wJ4qo87XRwpyhrq6bSay1_DKCVTgsKixNqq6rwwvGvaeOxZqKEG8vSWNZ6yfAyX9Ye5yepTGFmoYSXOC0TjnPlrhRo6jSdcUx89y9hmdc-MTwVX9e2pmmHaTgar2eQ0yeEXNzFjmIoqLihx64OH2oES3SJMjw6fKl4Hy3T5VLP3TvXLvvn8LEt66hvsD07S6R9puowNvz6iMaVkaO7iYRvaKWPfbpKBojOtZWBDNJpzirRypnZ8vQOVbwHeaxdPc9plkQXdoCkZziGb7cukg_rNkb5QaSc5pyFoahxoJAw959z0j6V_nJr5atV1DBmVOWtiZGsIDs78G4pvLkrVjZAOPVhJ5r4t_15gPJA0jwDRQwuKAuwWzt7nOJcLP8dXeX1wtbcr9NQFGVNL9yo_4gISr0SW84gW_mHUOg4YvpDZ3yt30xiwUvVLoXVusoc_UgDGGzgFwE4OqPSvRMD-5odH9SBezOoE8n4b2V5m9PZOVSsNjgeMJp_w2gpxCBJGxo1lWq8TjmzO0hEcgL0b7CONGoWrkze1EMXcjYlS_k2auTnRP5gaQEgU1P3hThx3X2KZXAmLrq9HNTpDLBOWJom9TQQ=w1916-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;Christakis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/iP8kLXNlwc_flWNlJwai9LoLDO-85CtbJuBhPjvv3clPbaLQp9aE5kwnT2ZUc5a97A8pY65k8MyWj9-3sMXfsP9K0T_hMGqLruwmst6ZW_GtL07XZIMkxEAipykh8saO9mdluHEvfWPHed3JlfkL20DOy_yJ_eFolVpG4EBIRAA63RGatawRm1ixf4eFVOgytt7plhz_9-kzK_2A20Nj49s7aDR6RLOs1Zm1YX7k2CMACaFIEniUwWAFsiHafdA_8zrTIXj1P8JFCI2DBKwiIm6dF0cmaVKnAYy3PsWM4qt6EAwFr1xsmTgt__w40yADfadCrr2mQCGvpODbTq4k2M4cE22_R2Wk6RZUVRlSpIXrR72YbDsXZyXjm4v5hbcaiRYtyyCwiU5YfVBz24GJ3wmlYK5k847rtQmxOuixf2ka1FW7A5tmaUJgOrplz0P7rdeHv1CMQaRffo1eaJO2Y7Q8UgUSPbP71Tt9PfVE10bJ2-tY1Mq-oFDfSnQI6RICyaUX8v8sUpJ3fXaIH1pXiJfLRRIALccJ_Guxh-prTvH75W_P717qfU0ihgAr7Kxf02kU-sN5rSz_4bYulMQAqLbjA1ICc7c=w1916-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;costa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RQyFC1OCUdxZemelA3YpVTSIMdBexaS0FYE87C8kxkjvy-RROlUTIvS0rvUTXVWNQx5YhK-UG5OqfhX4GWUVextKmWy7FHF4xTA9jPT2AvV7dtz6MVltg1qh4NzBr1gAYbPF61JDKm46QTAZa_PP_dJVjBESPgAB6eJZJCRWWToIztxD0hwQjCIz0qyXGEQsGGB52anAoCrzCtqBNjlFloix2GbMHHvPC9I6pvgW_L5MptTZsIKHrSvLsmjWnubfNmX6CX3S5YLEUqUlrESGqbG--V54oDQFS_KgTtiuaZvDk48SYgNywgsMvjkxXFW9PSFr2ZZVmykJzGFUwikxLUCLr9UHLjxd5QRGIGpLiEc3Q9W0PsvyFcyaz9xnAO-0AP4kTLhxS090Eckcx3XNcn0jqHizOfyuG1CkcNFmu4b59zxJ8H3pxj2-2uscLfDrw3UnoxoBlYnPnPQ6YoBE1Mh1cVjqcG8pvQ38UYfSbEQBldF8cShlS8RNUs-gQ7VUhLr55IYb2d3G_pxXPqh7odsNIOrN52ZDAvPLggGid8wBoLsm6biAz6wE4becKx8SLp9YcsrENGGgcHo_SnDL6swb83vQfDA=w1916-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;watermelon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/M2EbI30ZLbkPn1Br7aK7_1V2bzDhIYO8kn0g1FyuH5mjxdH-72RtufOhhFVzM3ZbhASxgiXF5677Ya4UU__PtpecJZ5cF4bapWRp2-IudmRWc4KuqMlS5JtdxHvfDfSr761CrSAbKuHkW38zdtJDWZA70dLmB9b3ulxRU7bFvTELPU0c3gjwyIknXWpIcN7Yf4VaBmFWDWJ33kualYrJFMkdpLg3O1Izq5Is3upC1NYnw4wra-FMEvXbnIDiYPYNysbwUXZ40w-HxQbnMWoGu_e9rpuoD-2cI7DCBkc4klRl9BX9AekrTcz12vaVrLL5xJZrl55UEg2ZtnTJXqejb1l4lBvVSxSJcg5amXEYgTNY_NrSEcNd6QxMzZc_UcLSepJa1eSf1yqnfU4zEDCJvCF49UkKsG9L3crn1PLPbG997u23rtc5L6NQ0eid-VokhALvRd5fIXUmvvafrmC8OC5QSnaw00f58RkOdfD4MSvK_xMKe61ctXNTCXPvzP0PjRK138NKukUAogpMSrR_SMfEnLm3wxQz4fk-Jl9uD_gwZSyuO0cL1t-x-xDurbsB87rPsNcbe5iYVjSCEy5n9YFCYHu6qFc=w1914-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;dancing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panikos welcomed our questions about Cypriot identity and the segregation that has occurred on the island since 1974. To Panikos, the Greek and Turkish Cypriots have a stronger bond with each other than they do with their mainland counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are the same people.” He said.  “[The enemy] plays with us. It was the British before, and it is the Turkish now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/SB_Uckn96dG7djYJbgh3VSL2ylJDRkGTq6HLpl6Ub6AwxWXSTTVbPYZnTga02XSGhpyiP4jIUZJrAnL90JqS10UiBxuJra6tQJeRFGlZ5E0xcCzfAERtgJjDhC_kjyUI5b83gi8ZruNYtzFcnY6mkWNO1zCp5tE-fDrk68Vj10Whk0RuxyjciCLSXlI72OOlCFHZDKGuqw8NWwTn9a3yHO4a34J3q22GwG-7G82GdO_dpUqEBzSQqJKFY0mdnNtL9K4NnjudMpqTTgxtatYlZxVgLBPNgyj9FTahcTkaqWOXxgl10aZCF3QeVW2U9kKwnosxNJghVvOpg0JwUfvdg6s645zv4EEUgo1srhDnxJqqji3Ed8TgOHJYvhlFRXlplz67HpJF8ptOeM_zL-19NFLk1ZfCGLG1J1PJpSpD6KL5TFpAQemOm3yxPIAuAc1XwJojK54q3ILrDNdh0Lbv41g7YtbOvkwMR6sUqJDH6BCNx6_zv5U6DtXLAaLXiaaTPjZog4Dm2I3H2xZjoOqvefZ2lmVvVy4YBHidl3rvDjsmmR9kJlGuUH0WbPQkuBXUiUZPZuuIZ9ZXpZHl_tkoVBl8ZhWrGnA=w1916-h1276-no&quot; alt=&quot;Panikos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panikos was born and raised in Famagusta, a large city now part of the occupied north.  He would like to see a unified Cyprus, but believes the matter is complicated by the settlers that have emigrated to the country in the last 40 years of separation, particularly the Turkish settlers in the north that inhabit previously Greek Cypriot villages. He also fears that the younger generation
 of Cypriots, those who only know a divided island, are too scared of the unknown to push for a unified Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Panikos says, “We love [the Turkish Cypriots]. Even if we do not speak the same language, we find a way to communicate.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/we-are-all-the-same-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/10/we-are-all-the-same-people/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Landing in Larnaca</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;salty-shores-and-hallowed-grounds&quot;&gt;Salty Shores and Hallowed Grounds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With thunderstorms in the afternoon forecast once again, we started our ten-mile hike to Larnaca bright and early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1792_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1792_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first stop when we arrived in the city was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larnaca_Salt_Lake&quot;&gt;Larnaca Salt Lake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1799_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1799_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the lake’s west bank stands a mosque that was impossible to miss so we made our way there to find the &lt;em&gt;Hala Sultan Tekke&lt;/em&gt; also known as the Mosque of Umm Haram, one of the holiest of shrines within Ottoman Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1820_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1820_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Umm Haram was the wet nurse of the Islamic prophet Muhammad and it is believed she passed away and was entombed here in the seventh century A.D. during the first Arab raids on Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1881_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1881_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1883_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1883_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These grounds, composed of the mosque, mausoleum, minaret, cemetery and living quarters have been preserved and are still being used for worship today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1846_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1846_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the southern side of the island is predominantly Orthodox Christian, this holy sight is preserved and functions today as a mosque. It stands as a reminder of the islands history and short-lived unification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1832_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1832_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the rest of our day, we’re just trying to stay dry…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1939_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1939_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and enjoying a Frappé in Larnaca.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_8918_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_8918_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/05/06/landing-in-larnaca/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/trekking/2016/05/06/landing-in-larnaca/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>trekking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Rain on my….Expedition</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-we-met-george&quot;&gt;How we met George&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our day started as usual, but the weather later dictated our course and led us to meet some incredible Cypriots…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_0715_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_0715_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left our campsite this morning in the port town of Zygi and headed east, not knowing exactly how far we would make it with dark clouds on the horizon and rain in the forecast. We made it 8km before tucking into a café for lunch and to wait out the storm, which had just begun. We met some locals, ate sandwiches, drank Cypriot coffee, played backgammon, and Anna &amp;amp; Vasili may or may not have fallen asleep sitting upright on the couch in the café.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1477_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1477_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1495_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1495_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when we thought the storm had passed, we geared up and continued walking east toward Larnaca. We made it 15 paces before the sky opened up and started dumping on us. Fortunately, George, a man we met at the café lives across the street and urgently ushered us into his dry, warm home. We were also fortunate to meet his wife Chris who prepared fresh &lt;a href=&quot;http://kopiaste.org/2007/11/bourekia-me-freskia-anari-pastries-with-fresh-anari-cheese/&quot;&gt;bourekia&lt;/a&gt; and stocked us up with oranges and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paximadia&quot;&gt;paximadia&lt;/a&gt; for the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1499_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1499_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a young man, George fought in the Cypriot military during the conflict leading up to the Turkish occupation. He was shot twice in those days but did not share the story of how it happened. Even still, he feels an affinity for Turkish-Cypriots.
As a child, George went to school and played along side Turkish Cypriots, all of them speaking both Greek and Turkish while interacting. He believes today’s Turkish-Cypriot are the same people he shares these memories with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1527_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1527_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_1531_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_1531_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, George would like to see Cyprus as a unified independent nation but fears that it will not happen due to the island’s strategic location. He thinks the United States, United Kingdom and Turkey have a shared interest in the island because it is a stepping-stone to the Middle East, Africa and Europe, and keeping the island segregated makes it easier to control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/thumb_IMG_2019_1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2019_1024.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you George and Chris for keeping us out of the rain, for the amazing bourekia, and for the insight on your island.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/05/don-t-rain-on-my-expedition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://circumnavigatingcyprus.github.io/en/interviews/2016/05/05/don-t-rain-on-my-expedition/</guid>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>interviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
